Finding Aid for the Alfred Leland Crabb Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Alfred Leland Crabb Papers
2016
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0089
32 linear feet
Biographical Sketch
Alfred Leland Crabb
Dr. Alfred Leland Crabb was born on January 22, 1884 in Plum Springs, Kentucky. He was the son of James Wade, a farmer, and Annie Arbuckle Crabb. He spent his elementary years in a one-room school at Plum Springs. In 1906, he embarked on an academic career and was subsequently educated at Bethel College, George Peabody College (today a part of Vanderbilt University), the University of Chicago, and Columbia University. He received his Ph.D. in 1925 from Peabody College. In 1911, he married Bertha Gardner. They had one son, Alfred Leland Crabb Jr., who taught English at the University of Kentucky.
Interspersed with the years of his formal education, he was teacher and later principal at several rural schools in Kentucky and Louisiana. After receiving his doctorate, he taught at what is now Western Kentucky University, where he soon became dean. In 1927 President Bruce Payne invited Crabb back to Peabody College, where he became professor of education, retiring in 1949. Crabb assumed the editorship of the Peabody Journal of Education in 1932, a position he retained until 1970. For this publication, and for the Peabody Reflector, he wrote hundreds of articles, essays, editorials, and poems.
A native of Warren County, Kentucky, Dr. Crabb wrote a biography of the development of Nashville, textbooks and articles for educational journals in addition to his novels. Crabb was best known for his trilogy of historical novels published between 1942 and 1945 that featured Nashville landmarks: Dinner at Belmont, Supper at the Maxwell House, and Breakfast at the Hermitage. The historical sites and traditional southern meals of their titles reflect Crabb's interest in the southern way of life in Nashville during the last half of the 19th century. These three novels span from the eve of the Civil War to 1897, the date of the Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition, and depict a period of upheaval for the city, state, and nation. Almost as popular as Crabb's Nashville trilogy was the Civil War trilogy that followed: Lodging at the Saint Cloud, A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga, and Home to Tennessee.
Southern food, folk music, tall tales, and detailed descriptions of Tennessee's flora and fauna are the hallmarks of Crabb's writing. Two of his most colorful creations, a nameless driver and his sidekick, College Grove impart a wide variety of southern and rural folklore and music.
Like many historical novelists of his time, Crabb adopted an old-fashioned style. Though writing in the modern era, he shared the values of the pre-modern society he described. His works featured everything that modernism lacked: continuity, certainty, and closure. Most importantly, Crabb revealed his pre-modernist sensibilities in the power he gave his characters to shape events rather than be shaped by them. His protagonists always viewed their lot as meaningful fate, never as random happenstance.
In addition to the Nashville and Civil War trilogies, he authored Journey to Nashville: A Story of the Founding, (1957) in which he described the adventures of the Wataugan parties on their trek through the wilderness and waters of Tennessee to establish the settlement first called Fort Nashborough. Home to the Hermitage, a novel about Andrew and Rachel Jackson toward the end of her life, was dramatized and presented on the Cavalcade of America radio program in 1948. He wrote two books about his native state, Home to Kentucky: A Novel of Henry Clay in 1953, and Peace at Bowling Green (1955) a story of a community from the pioneer times of 1803 to the end of the Civil War. In Nashville: Personality of a City (1960) he described the various people, places, and subjects for which he had demonstrated a fondness in his fictional work.
Crabb was a colorful personality. Memoirs of him attest that he always wore a coat and carried a scratch pad and stubby pencil in its pocket. While teaching at Peabody in the 1940s, the typist for his manuscripts was a student, future Playboy centerfold Bettie Page. On October 16, 1972, the Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce saluted Dr. Crabb as a "student-educator-editor-author and goodwill ambassador and Nashville civic leader for more than half a century."
Crabb died on Monday October 1st 1979 in a Lexington, Kentucky nursing home. The cause of death was “just accumulation of 96 years,” his son Alfred Leland Crabb Jr., of Lexington announced at his funeral in 1979.
After his death, by the Senate Joint Resolution No. 189 by Senator Henry, Crabb was honored by the state of Tennessee for his work in capturing the great state’s history and culture.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains Alfred Leland Crabb’s works and correspondences from 1910 to 1970.The first part covers correspondences with faculty, friends and publishing companies from 1925 to 1970. Crabb mainly worked with the Bobbs-Merrill Publishing Company and the Johnson Publishing Company.
The collection also contains letters sent out to promote his various books and writings. Crabb wrote many books in his life time and his manuscripts at different stages of his writing are included in the files. These include Dinner at Belmont, Supper at the Maxwell House, Home to the Hermitage, Home to Kentucky and A Mocking Bird Sang at Chickamauga.
Crabb also collected writings by various authors that he used for both book research and in the construction of teaching material. These along with some of his personal thoughts and reviews are included in the collection.
With a deep love for Tennessee and Kentucky, Crabb devoted much time into research on different aspects of southern life and culture. His research looks into the influence of different races in the south, folk music, architecture as well as many other southern life aspects over the years. These are well documented in the collection.
- Correspondence, 1925-1934
  - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, January-December 1935
  - Correspondence, January 1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, February 1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, March 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, April 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, May 1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June 1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, July 1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, August 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, October 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, November 1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, December 1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1936
  - Correspondence, January 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, February 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, March 1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, April 1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, May 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, July 1936 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, August 1936 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September 1936 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, October 1936 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, November 1936 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, December 1936 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1937
  - Correspondence, March 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, April 1937 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, June 1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July 1937 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, May 1937 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June 1937 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, August 1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, October 1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September 1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, December 1937 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, November 1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, February 1937 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January 1937 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1938-1939
  - Correspondence, January-February 1938 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1938 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May-June 1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July-August 1938 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, November 1938 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, December 1938 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, January-February 1939 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, May-June 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July-August 1939 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, September-October 1939 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1939 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1940-1946
  - Correspondence, January-May 1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1941 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1942 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1943 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January-August 1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1944 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1945 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1945 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Correspondence letters, 1942-1951
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1943 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1943 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January-December 1944 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, April-December 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January-December 1946 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, January-December 1947 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1948 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1949 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1949 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1950 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, January-July 1951 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Commenting on Peabody College and A. L. Crabb (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Requests for Peabody College and A. L. Crabb (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1947-1949
  - Correspondence, January-February 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, March–April 1947 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1947 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1947 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January – February 1948 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March – April 1948 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1948 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1948 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1948 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January – February 1949 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, March – April 1949 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1949 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1949 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1949 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1950 – 1952
  - Correspondence, January – February 1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, March – April 1950 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1950 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1950 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January – February 1951 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March – April 1951 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1951 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1951 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1951 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1951 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January – February 1952 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, March – April 1952 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1952 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1952 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1952 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1952 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1953 – 1955
  - Correspondence, January – February 1953 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1953 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1953 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January – February 1954 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March – April 1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May – June 1954 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July – August 1954 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, September – October 1954 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, November – December 1954 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January – February 1955 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, March – May 1955 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, June-July 1955 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, August-September 1955 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, October – December 1955 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1956-1964
  - Correspondence, January-September 1956 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, October-December 1956 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1957 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1961 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1961 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1962 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1962 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1964 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1964 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1965-1978
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, January – June 1966 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, July – December 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, June – December 1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January – May 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with E. B. Robert (1) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with E. B. Robert (2) (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous correspondences. (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Other Correspondence
  - E. Y. Chaplain (1) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - E. Y. Chaplain (2) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - E. Y. Chaplain (3) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - J. W. Brouillette (1) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - J. W. Brouillette (2) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - J. W. Brouillette (3) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - H. L. Donovan (1) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - H. L. Donovan (2) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - H. L. Donovan (3) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - H. L. Donovan (4) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - H. L. Donovan (5) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - H. L. Donovan (6) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - H. L. Donovan (7) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - J. C. Mathew (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Family (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Johnson Publishing Company (1) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Johnson Publishing Company (2) (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Correspondence with Bobbs-Merrill Company
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1941–1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1946-1951 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1952-1953 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1956-1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Correspondence on Writings
  - Lodging at St. Cloud (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - A Mocking Bird Sang at Chickamauga (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Correspondence on Writings
  - Journey to Nashville (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Supper at the Maxwell House (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Correspondence on Writings
  - Home to Kentucky (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Peace at Bowling Green (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Correspondence on Writings
  - Carbon of the First Draft of: A Mockingbird at Chickamauga (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Letters by Mrs. William. G. Harding (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Dinner At Belmont (Letters Volume 1) (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Correspondence on Writings
  - Reunion at Chattanooga. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Nashville Personality of a City (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Writings (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Correspondence on Writings
  - Home To Tennessee (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Breakfast At The Hermitage (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Writings
  - Selected writings on Peabody and Alfred Crabb I (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Selected writings on Peabody and Alfred Crabb II (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Personal writings I (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Personal writings II (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Personal writings III (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - A Mockingbird at Chickamauga manuscript Pg. (7-107) (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Writings I
  - Writings: Nomenclature & Mechanics in Catalogue Presentations. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Nashville the Suburb City. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Leadership in Nashville. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Nashville the Suburb. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - History of Peabody College. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Medium Well Done (First Draft). (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Medium Well Done (Writings). (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Nashville The Suburb II.(Writings) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Nashville The Suburb I.(Writings) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Andrew Jackson Chaplain Duelist. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Journal Of Rev. Francis Asbury (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Writings: We Believe In Books. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Flood Relief Louisville. (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Writings II
  - Chapters On Nashville (A. L. Crabb) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - The Marriage That Added Most To Nashville’s Quantity (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Sam Davis (Hero) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Your Grandparents Were There (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Dinner at Belmont (A Novel of Be Captured Nashville) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Are You Planning to Write a Forever Book. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Pepper (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The Whip-poor-will is A Southern Bird (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Shorty the Traitor (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - He Came To Stay James Robertson (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Wilkins Tannehill (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Modern Philanthropist Samuel Watkins (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - He Made Nashville Safe for the Baptists R. B. C. Howell (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Mister Nashville of All Time Andrews Jackson (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The Preserver of a Shrine. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. Duncan Doris (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Nashville’s Best Maker and User of Dollars John Overton (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Sent By Destiny (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Western Ho (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Plum Springs Piccolo (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - The Acts of Deliria (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - A Master Of Destiny (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - In Explanation (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Alexander Little Page Green (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Francis Briley Fogg (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - They Slept With Shoes On (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - The Novel Of The Past Historical Or Hysterical (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Guidance and Gray Hairs (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - A Piece Of Lovely Pie (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Filibuster William Walker (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - I’ll Prove Thee with Mirth (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - The Preserver Of A Shrine (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - The Baptists in Nashville (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - The Friendship (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - The Early Writers in Nashville (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - The Disappearing Smokehouse (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Eugene Caster Louis (The Parthenon Was His Idea) (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - John Berrien Lindley (The Benjamin Franklin of Nashville) (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Book Draft (Nashville) (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Six Remarkable Women Of Nashville (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Mixed Writings (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Extracts From Journal Of Joseph. R. Underwood (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Latin Mathematics and Natural Philosophy (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - A Battle Of Franklin (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - The Happy Ending (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - A New Era in Kentucky (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - He Came To Stay (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Advantages of Adolph (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Nulla Nubes Sine Argentina (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - A Most Remarkable Woman (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Nashville Is an Eating Town (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Teaching Then and Now (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - My Old Kentucky Home (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Peabody Reflector, March 1949 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Diary Of Susan Kirkman Vaughn (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - The Life Of The Teacher (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Happy Ending (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Making the Wounded Better (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Hope Springs Eternal (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - That Reminds Me (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Nashville Is an Eating Town (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - The Death And Burial Of Andrew Jackson (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Guidance & Gray Hairs (A. L. Crabb) (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - The Gathering Place Of The Books (A.L. Crabb) (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - In Defense Of Meddlesome Mattie Or What’s In The Tin Box (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - The Disappearing Smoke House (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Men That Are Fat (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Men Whom I Remember (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Curtains for the Last Day (Box 23, Folder 27)
- Writings III
  - Own Hand Writing Manuscript On Teaching. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Medium Well Done (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Owed To June Twenty First (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Personalities (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Soliloquy Of Kenneth Cooper On Being Invited (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Andrew Jacksons Nashville (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Nashville Suburb to the Kitchen (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Prologue To The Last Day (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - What Professional Qualifications Should Faculty Members Of Teachers Colleges And Normal Schools Posses (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Lines to Alumnus (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Partial Mixed Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Gathering Place Of The Boots (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Guidance and Gray Hairs (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The Economic And Social Beginnings Of Tennessee (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Education And Kentucky (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Welcome To Travelers Rest (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Andrew Jacksons Nashville (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Null Nubes Sine Argentina (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Early Writers Of Nashville (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Early Writers Of Nashville(2) (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Civil War Research (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Long Pants For The Last Day (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Please Thank You & Excuse Me (Box 24, Folder 18)